Guide to the John Lowenthal Papers TAM.190
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Alger Hiss Research Files, 1934-2003; 81540
  - Nikolaevich, Nikolai: Re: Hiss, Oct 1992, 1993; cuid8368; 81601 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Nixon, Richard: Speeches, re: Hiss, 1952, 1954; cuid8369; 81600 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Packer, Herbert: Re: Woodstock Typewriter, 1970; cuid8370; 81599 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Pavlov, Vitaliy, undated, 1999-2000; cuid8371; 81598 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Penn, Arthur: Re: Sudoplatov/"Pumpkin Papers", 1994; cuid8372; 81597 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Piel, Eleanor Jackson: Correspondence, 1974; cuid8373; 81596 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Pikhovia, Rudolf Germanovich: Re: Hiss, undated, 1992-1993; cuid8374; 81595 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Pilpel, Harriet: Correspondence, May 14, 1974; cuid8375; 81594 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Pressman, Lee: Re: Hiss, 1949, 1969, 1977-1994; cuid8376; 81593 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: Re: Hiss, undated, 1983, 1999; cuid8377; 81592 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Raushenbush, Stephen: Correspondence, 1934-1935; cuid8378; 81591 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss-Reuben FOIA Suit, 1974-1975, 1980, 1984-1985; cuid8379; 81590 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Reuben, William A.: Re: Allen Weinstein, 1992; cuid8380; 81589 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Rosen, William, 1948-1949; cuid8381; 81588 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Ruben, Albert: Correspondence, Sep 25, 2001; cuid8382; 81587 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Russian/Soviet Archives: Re: Hiss, undated, 1991-1992; cuid8383; 81586 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Salant, Stephen: Re: FBI's Counter Intelligence Programs, 1959-1960; cuid8384; 81585 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Salant, Stephen: Re: "Pumpkin Papers", undated, 1974-1975; cuid8385; 81584 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Sayre, Francis B.: Correspondence, Jan 15, 1949; cuid8386; 81583 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Schroeter, Leonard: Correspondence, Apr 11, 1975; cuid8387; 81582 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Shattuck, John H.: American Civil Liberties Union, Nov 21, 1973; cuid8388; 81581 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Shepherd, Peter: Correspondence, 1998-1999; cuid8389; 81580 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Solow, Robert: Re: FBI Interview, Jan 28, 1976; cuid8390; 81579 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Sproul, Kathleen: Correspondence, Apr 29, 1962; cuid8391; 81578 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Stevenson, Matthew: Re: "Ales", undated, 1987, 1995-2002; cuid8392; 81577 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Stossel, Frederic: Correspondence, May 2, 1973; cuid8393; 81576 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Tanenhaus, Sam, 1989-1993, 1998-2001; cuid8394; 81575 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Thron, C. Davis: Correspondence, 1974, 1994; cuid8395; 81574 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Toledano, Ralph de, 1950, 1957, 1977-1990; cuid8396; 81573 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Alger Hiss (pp.1-70) (Note: R-7771C/21 Begins Here), Nov 9, 1976, Mar 7, 1978-Mar 8, 1978; cuid8397; 81572 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Alger Hiss (pp.71-169), Nov 10, 1976; cuid8398; 81571 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Alger Hiss (pp.170-252), Jan 22, 1977; cuid8399; 81570 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Alger Hiss (pp. 253-337), Jan 22, 1977; cuid8400; 81569 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Nathan Witt (pp. 338-400), Jan 5, 1977; cuid8401; 81568 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Ralph de Toledano (pp. 401-448), Apr 6, 1977; cuid8402; 81567 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, John Francis Cronin and Mr. and Mrs. Donald Hiss (pp. 449-510), undated, Apr 8, 1977; cuid8403; 81566 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Mike, Pat and Raymond Catlett (pp. 511-541), Apr 8, 1977; cuid8404; 81565 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Ramos Feehan, Harold Rosenwald and Mr. Doyle (pp. 542-652), Apr 26, 1977-Apr 27, 1977; cuid8405; 81564 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Edward Murtagh, Malcolm Crowley, Isaac Don Levine and David Zablodowsky (pp 653-652a), May 13, 1977; cuid8406; 81563 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Robert Stripling and Congressman Herbert (pp. 653a-764), undated; cuid8407; 81562 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Vincent Reno and Sam Krieger (pp. 765-859), Aug 15, 1977; cuid8408; 81561 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Harold Shapero and Ordman Clubb (pp. 860-981), Sep 7, 1977, Sep 15, 1977; cuid8409; 81560 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Margaret Halsey and Alger Hiss, Gussie Feinstein (pp. 982-1139/39), Nov 17, 1977; cuid8410; 81559 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Vincent Shaw (pp. 1113-1164), Mar 18, 1978; cuid8411; 81558 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Turner, Catherine: Correspondence, 1993-1994; cuid8412; 81557 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - University of Texas at Austin, School of Law: Re: Alger Hiss, 1970-1971; cuid8413; 81556 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Van Doren, Mark: (Includes Whittaker Chambers Correspondence), 1926, 1948-1949; cuid8414; 81555 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander: Re: Court Case, 1999-2001; cuid8415; 81554 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander: Re: Court Case, Jan 2002-Apr 2002; cuid8416; 81553 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander: Re: Court Case, May 2002-Oct 2002; cuid8417; 81552 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Venona: Documents, 1950-1956; cuid8418; 81551 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Venona: Re: "Ales", 1956, 1996, 1999; cuid8419; 81550 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Volkogonov, Dmitri, undated, 1992-1994; cuid8420; 81549 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Vorontsov, Yuri: Re: Hiss, 1992-1993; cuid8421; 81548 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Weinstein, Allen: Re: Perjury, 1978; cuid8422; 81547 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Weissberger, L. Arnold: Re: Hiss, 1965-1978; cuid8423; 81546 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Werchen, Raymond: Writings Re: Hiss, 1973, 1976; cuid8424; 81545 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Weyl, Nathaniel, undated, 1952; cuid8425; 81544 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Whitman, Alden, 1974-1975; cuid8426; 81543 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Zeligs, Meyer: Correspondence, 1962-1965, 1977-1978; cuid8427; 81542 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Zeligs, Meyer: Re: Friendship and Fratricide, undated, 1963-1970; cuid8428; 81541 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Series II: Subject Files, 1942-2003; 81036
  - Abt, John J., 1953, 1958, 1977; cuid8429; 81539 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Adams,: "Nothing to Fear but Fear Itself," Typescript (British Broadcasting Service), undated; cuid8430; 81538 (Box 6, Folder 1a)
  - Adler, Mortimer: Correspondence, Nov 1, 1976-Dec 1, 1976; cuid8431; 81537 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Aldrich, Richard: Re: The Haunted Wood, May 1, 2003; cuid8432; 81536 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Alger Hiss Case in America and Russia (JL): Typescript, 1993; cuid8433; 81535 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Alger Hiss: The Perfect Victim: Correspondence and Typescript, 2003; cuid8434; 81534 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Alger Hiss and William A. Reuben v. U.S. Department of Justice et al., Sep 2, 1981; cuid8435; 81533 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Allen, George: Re: J. Edgar Hoover, Homosexuality, 1946, 1987; cuid8436; 81532 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Andrew, Christophe, 1999-2001; cuid8437; 81531 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Association of American Indian Affairs: Memorandum, Jun 4, 1984; cuid8438; 81530 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bannerman, Robert L.: Handwritten Notes, re:, Mar 30, 1977; cuid8439; 81529 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Barksdale, Calvert: Seaver Books, re: Coram Nobis Manuscript, 1987; cuid8440; 81528 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bogert, Carroll, 1994; cuid8441; 81527 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bonin, Richard: 60 Minutes, 1992; cuid8442; 81526 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Book Two: Unsigned Typescript, undated; cuid8443; 81525 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Botstein, Leon, 1981, 1992-1993; cuid8444; 81524 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Boughton, James: Articles and Correspondence, 2000-2001; cuid8445; 81523 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Brent, Jonathan: Yale University Press, 1992-1993; cuid8446; 81522 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Breyer, Henry W. Jr.: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1950; cuid8447; 81521 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Brick, Richard: Correspondence, undated, 1984-1985; cuid8448; 81520 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Brick, Richard: Silo Cinema, 1976-1981, 1992; cuid8449; 81519 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Brown, William Adams: Correspondence, Feb 6, 1950; cuid8450; 81518 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Bush, Flora Wilhelm: "A Discussion of the Case of Alger Hiss", 1979; cuid8451; 81517 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Cammer, Harold I.: Letter to the Editor re: Lionel Trilling/Chambers, Apr 7, 1975; cuid8452; 81516 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Cantwell, Robert, 1973, 1977-1978; cuid8453; 81515 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Carlsen, Carl E.: Correspondence, 1975, 1980; cuid8454; 81514 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Cass, Stewart: Correspondence, 2003; cuid8455; 81513 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Chaly, Ingeborg: "Rhetorical Discretion and Legal Constraints in Jury Instructions: A Comparative Analysis of the Two Charges to the Jury in the Alger Hiss Perjury Trials", 1981; cuid8456; 81512 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Chamberlain, John: Handwritten Notes, re:, Apr 21, 1977; cuid8457; 81511 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Chambers, John: Handwritten Notes, re:, Jan 19, 1977; cuid8458; 81510 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Homosexuality, 1948-1950, 1974-1977, 1999; cuid8459; 81509 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Investigation of, Nov 1948; cuid8460; 81508 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Notes for Book, re:, Sep 6, 1999; cuid8461; 81507 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Notes re: Break with Communist Party, Feb 13, 1994; cuid8462; 81506 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Writings in The Saturday Evening Post, 1952; cuid8463; 81505 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Chandler, Tertius: Correspondence, 1976; cuid8464; 81504 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Clark, Blair: The Nation, Correspondence, 1976; cuid8465; 81503 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Clubb, Oliver Edmund, 1977-1978, 1989; cuid8466; 81502 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Cold War International History Project: "The Hiss Case and Soviet Archives," Typescript (drafts), Dec 17, 1993-Mar 16, 1994; cuid8467; 81501 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Cold War International History Project: "The Hiss Case and Soviet Archives," Typescript (drafts), Mar 18, 1994-Apr 25, 1994; cuid8468; 81500 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Commentary: Correspondence, 1990-1993; cuid8469; 81499 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Committee on Un-American Activities, U.S. House of Representatives (HUAC): Pamphlets, 1948; cuid8470; 81498 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Communist Party, U.S.A., 1946-1951; cuid8471; 81497 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Compton, James: "Anti-Communism in American Life Since the Second World War" and Correspondence, 1973, 1993; cuid8472; 81496 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Connelley, Earl J: Affidavit, Mar 12, 1952; cuid8473; 81495 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence: General, undated, 1962-1963, 1970-1999; cuid8474; 81494 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence: Re: John Earl Haynes, 2000-2001; cuid8475; 81493 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence: Re: William A. Reuben's Writings, 1995-1997; cuid8476; 81492 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Counterattack, 1948; cuid8477; 81491 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Cowley, Michael: Clippings and Correspondence, 1977-1981; cuid8478; 81490 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Craig, Bruce: "A Matter of Espionage: Alger Hiss, Harry Dexter White and Igor Gouzenko-The Canadian Connection Reassessed," Typescript, 2000; cuid8479; 81489 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Craig, Bruce: Re: Opening Hiss Grand Jury Records, 1996-1999; cuid8480; 81488 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Craig, Bruce: Writings, undated, 1990, 1996; cuid8481; 81487 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cronin, John F., 1940s, 1968-1980, 1994; cuid8482; 81486 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cross, Claude B.: "'The Assistance of Counsel for His Defense': Is This Becoming a Meaningless Guarantee?" American Bar Association Journal, Dec 1952; cuid8483; 81485 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Currie, Laughlin, 1940-1959, 2002; cuid8484; 81484 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Davies, John: Correspondence, Jun 2, 1942; cuid8485; 81483 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Davis, John F.: Handwritten Notes, re:, Dec 30, 1976; cuid8486; 81482 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Dean, John, 1974-1977; cuid8487; 81481 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Douglas, William O., 1976, 2003; cuid8488; 81480 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Doyle, Jerome, 1948, 1977-1978, 1999; cuid8489; 81479 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The Dreyfus Case and the Hiss Case: Points of Similarity and Points of Difference, Typescript, undated; cuid8490; 81478 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Eddy, George: Chambers-Hiss, Typescript, 1959-1960; cuid8491; 81477 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Einstein, Albert: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1984-1988; cuid8492; 81476 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Elsten, David: Hiss/Venona Documentary, 2000-2001; cuid8493; 81475 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Elsten, David: Thames Television, Inc., 1978-1983; cuid8494; 81474 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Espionage Law: Handwritten Notes, re:, undated, 1997; cuid8495; 81473 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Eye of a Bird: Play re: Hiss, undated; cuid8496; 81472 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - FBI: FOIA Request re: John Lowenthal, 1978; cuid8497; 81471 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Field, Noel: Article and Handwritten Notes, Re:, 1993-1994, 2000-2002; cuid8498; 81470 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Footnote on a Historic Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, No. 78 Civ. 3433 (JL) (Nation Institute), 1983; cuid8499; 81469 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Gates, John: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1977-1978; cuid8500; 81468 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Glazer, Nathan: The National Interest, 1993; cuid8501; 81467 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Global American Television, Inc.: Correspondence, 1993; cuid8502; 81466 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Gordievsky, Oleg A.: Article and Clippings, re:, 1990, 1995; cuid8503; 81465 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Gorizontov, Leonid: East European Scientific and Information Agency, undated, 1992; cuid8504; 81464 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Griffin, Kevin W.: Correspondence and Handwritten Notes, re:, 1978; cuid8505; 81463 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Gwynn, Beatrice: Correspondence, 1976, 1997; cuid8506; 81462 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Gwynn, Beatrice: "The Discrepancies in the Evidence," Typescript, undated; cuid8507; 81461 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Gwynn, Beatrice: Translation of Augusto Marcelli's Article in Paese Sera re: Hiss' Visit to Italy, Sep 27, 1970; cuid8508; 81460 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Halperin, Morton: Re: Herbert Hoover, Official and Confidential Files, 1975-1976; cuid8509; 81459 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Halperin, Morton: Re: Wiretapping, 1976; cuid8510; 81458 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Hamilton, James: Correspondence, 1979, 1982, 1999-2003; cuid8511; 81457 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Hamilton, James: Writings, undated, 1981, 1993-1999; cuid8512; 81456 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Handwritten Notes: Re: Hiss, 1950-1979, 1999; cuid8513; 81455 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Haury, Agnese Nelms (formerly Agnese Nelms Lindley and Agnese Nelms Lockwood): Correspondence and Memoranda, 1974-1981, 1992-2001; cuid8514; 81454 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Heller, Howard: Correspondence, 1984; cuid8515; 81453 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (I), undated; cuid8516; 81452 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (II), undated; cuid8517; 81451 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (III), undated; cuid8518; 81450 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (IV), undated; cuid8519; 81449 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Hiss, Alger: Re: "Ales"/Mars, Jan 2, 1949; cuid8520; 81448 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1948-1950; cuid8521; 81447 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1961-1966; cuid8522; 81446 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1967-1974; cuid8523; 81445 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1975-1977; cuid8524; 81444 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1978, 1980; cuid8525; 81443 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1981-1983; cuid8526; 81442 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Hiss, Alger: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Files I, 1940s; cuid8527; 81441 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Hiss, Alger: FOIA II, 1940s; cuid8528; 81440 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Hiss, Alger: FOIA III, 1940s; cuid8529; 81439 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Hiss, Alger: FBI Report, 1941-1942, 1948; cuid8530; 81438 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Hiss, Alger: Law Talk, undated; cuid8531; 81437 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Hiss, Alger: McCarthy Era, Notes re:, 1980s; cuid8532; 81436 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Hiss, Alger: Nye Committee, Hiss Questions Bernard Baruch, 1990s; cuid8533; 81435 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Hiss, Alger: Obituaries, Nov 16, 1996-Nov 19, 1996; cuid8534; 81434 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Hiss, Alger: Re: Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1980s; cuid8535; 81433 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Hiss, Alger: Yalta Conference, Articles re:, undated, Nov 1955; cuid8536; 81432 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. U.S.A., 1950; cuid8537; 81431 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. U.S.A., 1952; cuid8538; 81430 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 1-209), Nov 4, 1948; cuid8539; 81429 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 210-440)), Nov 5, 1948; cuid8540; 81428 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Mrs. Esther Chambers, Direct (pp. 441-640), Nov 17, 1948; cuid8541; 81427 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Mrs. Esther Chambers, Direct (pp. 641-715), Nov 17, 1948; cuid8542; 81426 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 716-829), Nov 17, 1948; cuid8543; 81425 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 830-1061), Nov 17, 1948; cuid8544; 81424 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 1062-1290), Feb 18, 1949; cuid8545; 81423 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, (pp. 1291-1382), Mar 25, 1949; cuid8546; 81422 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss, Richard Strasburger and Besse Brown Strasberger v. Robert E. Hampton et al., 1972; cuid8547; 81421 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Case: Baltimore Depositions, Notes, 1976, 1993-1994; cuid8548; 81420 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: Baltimore Exhibits (Lowenthal reference file, mostly defense materials: memos, correspondence, background on Woodstock typewriter, etc.), 1948-1949, 1962-1976; cuid8549; 81419 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Bykov, Boris, 1945, 1949, 2003; cuid8550; 81418 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: Catlett, Mike and Pat, 1949, 1977-1978; cuid8551; 81417 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: Chambers, Whittaker and Esther, undated, 1945-1952; cuid8552; 81416 (Box 10, Folder 4a)
  - Hiss Case: Character Witnesses, Individuals and Organizations, 1948; cuid8553; 81415 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: Collins, Henry, 1948, 1951; cuid8554; 81414 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: Davis, John, 1948-1949; cuid8555; 81413 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: "Die Deutsche Regierung...": Aide-Memoire, on 1930s Trade (in German; photostat; labeled 611.6231/987), Undated; cuid8556; 81412 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: Dulles, John Foster, Jul 1, 1949; cuid8557; 81411 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: Fearon, Edwin, 1949; cuid8558; 81410 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Case: FBI Memos, 1948-1949, 1956, 1963-1978; cuid8559; 81409 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Case: Government Exhibits (List and misc. copies, 1st and 2nd trials?), undated, 1938-1949; cuid8560; 81408 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Hiss Case: Inslerman, Felix, Jan 21, 1949; cuid8561; 81407 (Box 10, Folder 12a)
  - Hiss Case: In the Matter of Alger Hiss, Appendix to the Brief for the Petitioner, 1974-1975; cuid8562; 81406 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Hiss Case: In the Matter of Alger Hiss, Brief for the Petitioner, undated; cuid8563; 81405 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Hiss Case: In the Matter of Alger Hiss, Brief of the Bar Counsel, May 1975; cuid8564; 81404 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Brief for Petitioner-Appellant, Nov 30, 1982; cuid8565; 81403 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Brief for Respondent-Appellee, USA, Jul 15, 1982; cuid8566; 81402 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Brief for the United States in Opposition, Oct 1983; cuid8567; 81401 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Memorandum in Support of Petitioner's Motion to Grant Writ of Coram Nobis, Jul 8, 1980; cuid8568; 81400 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Memorandum of Law in Opposition to Petitioner's Application for a Writ of Error Coram Nobis, Jul 27, 1978; cuid8569; 81399 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Memorandum of Law in Opposition to Petitioner's Application for a Writ of Error Coram Nobis and to Petitioner's Application for an Evidentiary Hearing and Discovery, Nov 20, 1979; cuid8570; 81398 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Opinion of Richard Owen, Jul 15, 1982; cuid8571; 81397 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Petition for Reargument and Rehearing En Banc, Feb 24, 1983; cuid8572; 81396 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, Jun 17, 1983; cuid8573; 81395 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Petition for Writ of Error Coram Nobis, Jul 27, 1978; cuid8574; 81394 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Reply Brief for Petitioner-Appellant, Feb 9, 1983; cuid8575; 81393 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Reply Brief in Support of Petition for a Writ of Certiorari, Sep 30, 1983; cuid8576; 81392 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Hiss Case: Investigators, 1949-1950; cuid8577; 81391 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: Jurors, 1949, 1977-1978; cuid8578; 81390 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Lane, Chester, 1950; cuid8579; 81389 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: New England Spectrochemical Laboratories, 1956; cuid8580; 81388 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: Oral Testimonies, Notes, 1940s, 1970s; cuid8581; 81387 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: Pigman, Ward, 1948-1949; cuid8582; 81386 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: Reinstatement to Massachusetts State Bar, Amicus Curia Brief of the Boston Bar Association, May 7, 1975; cuid8583; 81385 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: Reinstatement to Massachusetts State Bar, Application, Jan 7, 1975; cuid8584; 81384 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: Reinstatement to Massachusetts State Bar, On Report by a Justice of the Supreme Court for Suffolk County, [1975]; cuid8585; 81383 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: Russian Archives, 1992; cuid8586; 81382 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Case: Schmahl, Horace, undated, 1941-1952, 1971-1975; cuid8587; 81381 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Case: Time, Life, Fortune, Editors, 1930-1959; cuid8588; 81380 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Appeal from a Judgment of the District Court for the Southern District of New York, Dec 7, 1950; cuid8589; 81379 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Brief for Appellant, undated; cuid8590; 81378 (Box 11, Folder 14)